你们听说了那个发现在13岁时很受欢迎的人
Did you hear about this study that found people
在日后会很难获取成功
that were cool and popular at 13
的研究吗?
have problems succeeding later in life?
嗯 我还好 我在13岁的时候挺受欢迎的
Hmm. I'm doing okay, and I was very popular at 13.
在学校里
In school?
不 在家
Oh, no. At home.
仆人们会唱歌给我听
The servants would sing to me,
听我讲笑话会笑出声...
laugh at my jokes...
真希望我能知道他们的名字
I wish I knew their names.
研究提到了那些不受欢迎的小孩吗?
Does the study say what happens to the unpopular kids?
你说呢... 早上你床头睡的那位就是
You tell me... you woke up in bed with one.
听着
Listen to this.
我刚刚收到了Wil Wheaton的邮件
I just received an e-mail from Wil Wheaton.
Leonard Nimoy的儿子正在拍一部纪录片
Leonard Nimoy's son is working on a documentary
他父亲去世前 他俩一起拍的
that he started with his father before he passed away.
关于Spock先生和他对美国文化的影响
It's about Mr. Spock and his impact on our culture.
嗯
Hmm.
他给你写邮件干嘛?
Why is he writing to you?
他们正在找粉丝做采访
Well, they're looking for fans to interview,
Wil觉得我很合适
and Wil thought I'd be good for it.
嘿 击个掌
Oh. Hey, high five.
绝不要
Absolutely not.
对了 Penny
Yeah, Penny,
你有过上镜的经验
you spent some time in front
有什么建议吗?
of the camera. Any words of advice?
有的 不要因为导演叫你脱衣服
Yes. Don't take your shirt off
你就真脱
just because the director said so.
这是一个关于Spock先生的纪录片
This is a documentary about Mr. Spock.
我敢肯定如果有裸露的镜头 也会很上档次的
I'm sure if there's nudity, it will be tasteful.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 * * 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall * * We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第九季第7集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥祝夏夏考试顺利
校对: UUUUUU
翻译: AU薇 李小宝 凤梨酥
嘿 有时间么
Hey. You got a minute?
没有
Not really.
西哥特人跟我拼命呢
Visigoths are kind of up my butt right now.
把游戏暂停一下 Howard
Pause the game, Howard.
"Howard"? 啊哦
"Howard"? Uh-oh.
腾点空间 西哥特人
Make room, Visigoths.
怎么了?
'Sup?
我们得谈谈重新装修的问题
We need to talk about redecorating this place.
哦不是吧 又是这个
Oh, no, not this again. Look,
我知道你在这儿长大 对这里的一切
I get that you grew up here and you're attached to things
保持原状抱有执念 但是...
looking a certain way, but...
我也想让这里像我的家
I want this to feel like my house, too.
亲爱的 这里当然是你的家
Oh, honey, of course it's your house.
不然你什么老是打扫呢?
Why else would you be cleaning it all the time?
好吧 重新开始
All right. Let's start over.
我准备重新装修
I'm redecorating.
家具 地毯 墙纸
The furniture, the carpeting, the walls.
我要把所有看不顺眼的东西都换了
I'm changing everything that depresses me when I look at it.
你最好别成为其中之一
Try not to be one of those things.
我能说句话么?
May I say something?
是你爸爸在小时候离开了你现在你妈妈又死了
Is it about how I can't have new wallpaper
所以我不能装新墙纸吗?
'cause your dad left when you were little and your mom died?
没事了
Never mind.
嘿 Amy 我是Sheldon
Hello, Amy. It's Sheldon.
我知道我们已经分手了
Yeah, I-I know that we're broken up, but
我留言是因为我估计你可能想来看
I'm leaving this message because I thought perhaps you'd like
我为一部关于Spock先生的纪录片接受的采访
to watch me be interviewed for a documentary about Mr. Spock.
或者用我的叫法 Spock录片
Or as I like to call it, a Spockumentary.
是的 我打算在
Yeah, I'm going to use
采访中用这个梗 所以
that joke in the interview, so try to laugh
要像第一次听到那样狂笑哦
like you're hearing it for the first time.
歇斯底里的那种 嗯?
You know, hysterically, hmm?
再带上一点悲伤的情绪因为我已经从你的生活中消失了
And with a tinge of sadness that I'm no longer in your life.
想出Spock录片的人是我
I'm the one who thought of "Spockumentary"
而我还像第一次听到那样狂笑
And I'm laughing like I did the first time I heard it.
嗨
Hello.
嘿 Sheldon
Hey, Sheldon.
这是Adam Nimoy
This is Adam Nimoy.
- 很高兴见到你  - 哦 很高兴见到你
- Nice to meet you.  - Oh, it's nice to meet you.
我非常喜欢你父亲的作品
I admire your father's work very much.
我并不是每天都能遇见生命旅程
It's not every day I get to meet someone whose life's journey
从我心目中的英雄的阴囊里开始的人
began in my hero's scrotum.
我跟你说过 这家伙很极品
I told you. This guy is gold.
你在干什么?
Whatcha doing? Oh!
用我妈的方法给自己做个腊肠三明治
Making myself a bologna sandwich like my mom used to make me
就像我爸离家后 我妈去世前她给我做的一样
after my dad left, but before she died.
听着 我想着
Okay, listen, I'm thinking
在房子的问题上我们可能可以折衷一下
that maybe we can compromise on the house.
我在听
I'm listening.
我们先重装一个房间看看效果如何
Let's just redo one room and see how it goes.
这还差不多
That is reasonable.
但是哪间呢?
But what room?
这间怎么样?
How 'bout this one?
没门 这是我和我妈互动最多的一间
No way. No, this is the room I associate the most with my mom.
那浴室怎么样?
Then how 'bout the bathroom?
我要反悔
I want to change my answer.
好的 那就餐厅
Fine. Then the dining room.
我们不太用餐厅
I guess we didn't use it very often.
除非有客人
Unless we had company.
在我爸离开后不常有 而在我妈死后
Which didn't happen much after my dad left and not at all
就完全没有了...
after my mom...
好极了! 我要去选几个油漆样本
Great! I'm gonna go pick out paint samples.
好的 我们就简单谈几句
All right, we're just gonna have a conversation.
假装这里没有摄像机
Pretend the camera's not here.
好的 这最好不是
All right. But this better not be
什么精心设计的让我脱衣服的诡计
some elaborate scheme to get me out of my shirt.
你认识Adam多久了?
How long have you known Adam?
有些年头了
A few years. Mm-hmm.
你把他找回来干嘛?
And what are you getting him back for?
从你的名字和职业开始吧
Let's start with your name and occupation.
Sheldon Cooper博士 理论物理学家 供职于加州理工大学
Dr. Sheldon Cooper, theoretical physicist, Caltech.
关于Spock这个角色你最初的记忆是怎样的?
And what is your earliest memory of the character Spock?
星际迷航原初系列里我看的第一集
The first episode of Star Trek: The Original Series I ever saw
是"伽利略七号"
was "The Galileo Seven."
Spock刚刚在金牛二号行星上登陆
Uh, Spock had just landed on the planet Taurus II.
这时候我哥走了进来 坐在我头上
Then my brother came in, sat on my head,
说 "吃屁吧"
and said, "Eat farts."
那天之后 我就迷上了它
After that day, I was hooked.
指的是星际迷航
On Star Trek,
不是我哥的括约肌烹饪
not my brother's sphincter-based cuisine.
Spock吸引你的地方在哪?
What was it about Spock that appealed to you?
我想是同样吸引了所有人的东西
I think the same thing that appeals to people everywhere,
一个金色的 理性的
the dream of a cold, rational world
泯灭人类感情的世界的梦想
entirely without human emotion.
Spock是从
Spock came
一个完全由逻辑统治的行星上来的
from a planet governed only by logic.
在瓦肯星 当你的哥哥问你
You know, on Vulcan, when your brother asks,
"你为什么自残?"的时候 回答是
"Why are you hitting yourself?" the answer is,
"我没有啊
"I'm not.
是你在动我的手臂"
You're moving my arm."
关于此他的评价是
To which he says,
“真厉害”
"Fascinating."
然后俩人一起快乐的看教育台
And then you both watch educational television.
哦 他说那些话的时候
Aw. When he says things like that,
我真想抱抱他给他安慰
I just want to hug him and make everything better.
我哥哥也对我很差
My brother was mean to me, too.
肯定是你太熊了
Yeah, you probably had it coming.
你有Spock系列收藏品吗?
Do you have any Spock collectibles?
多了去了
I have many.
我最宝贝的是我的贴心好友Penny
My most treasured is an autographed napkin
送我的签名餐巾纸
given to me by my very thoughtful friend Penny.
她就坐在那儿
That's her over there.
嗨!
Hi!
看哪
Look at that.
没脱衣服 进了电影
I'm in a movie, my shirt stayed on.
能看看这张餐巾纸吗
Can we see the napkin?
当然 稍等
Of course. Excuse me.
马上就来
This will just take a moment.
我们什么时候有了墙嵌保险箱?
When did we get a wall safe?
地嵌保险箱满了的时候
When there was no more room in the floor safe.
什么时候多了地嵌保险箱?
When did we get a floor safe?
装监控摄像头的时候
When we got the security camera.
还有监控摄像头?
There's a security camera?
潜水侠 从2012开始为您守护
Aquaman, protecting your home since 2012.
天哪 我们在那张沙发上嘿咻过
Oh, my God. We've done things on that couch.
我一清二楚
Yeah. You don't have to tell me.
你岳父在厨房里?
So, your father-in-law is in there right now?
对 挺我
Yes. So back me up.
房子保持原样就很好 明白
The house is good the way it is. Oh, okay. Got it.
嘿 你们在干嘛
Hey. What's going on?
嘿 嘿 Raj
Hey. Hey, Raj.
爸爸和我准备把这面墙打掉
Dad and I were just talking about taking down this wall.
真的吗? 这可是面很好的墙
You sure? It's a... pretty great wall.
怎么说?
What's so great about it?
抱歉 我尽力了
I'm sorry. I did what I could.
真的吗? 你带Raj来替你说话?
Seriously? You brought Raj over to take your side?
你有你爸爸
Your dad's on your side.
他可不是来帮我说话的 他来当免费工
He's not on my side. He's doing all the work for free.
您真是慷慨
That is so generous of you.
我换边站了
I'd like to switch sides.
听着..
Look, uh...
你不可能打掉这面墙
I don't even think you can take this wall down
它可是承重的
'cause it's load-bearing.
这挺容易
Well, it's easy to find out.
到地板下面地基里检查一下就行
Just go into the crawlspace under the house and check.
为什么你还不滚回印度?
When is your visa up?
他不仅在这上面给我签了名
Not only is it signed to me
还用这张纸擦了嘴
but this is where he wiped his mouth.
所以我手上拿的是Leonard Nimoy的DNA
So we are currently in the presence of Leonard Nimoy's DNA.
Adam不算Leonard Nimoy的DNA吗?
Um, doesn't Adam count as Leonard Nimoy's DNA?
无意冒犯 但我这可是100%的Nimoy
No offense, but this is pure 100% Nimoy.
因为你母亲的遗传 你只有50%Nimoy的DNA
Because of your mother, you're only 50%.
这虽然没什么坏处
Which isn't bad,
但是你用来擦嘴的东西只会被扔掉
but anything that you wipe your mouth on gets thrown away.
纸巾的话题就到此为止
Okay, enough about the napkin.
你还在里面藏了什么?
What else you hiding in there?
你想知道吗?
Wouldn't you like to know?
- 当然想  - 那好吧
- I would.  - All right then.
看到了吗 都是我的宝贝
See? Just my valuables.
- 我的护照 我的遗嘱...  - 你还有遗嘱?
- My passport, uh, my will...  - You have a will?
当然了 我的一比十八大小的Wil Wheaton手办
Yeah... my 1/18 scale Wil Wheaton action figure.
我还有其他类型的遗嘱
I also have the other kind of will,
我希望死后这个模型能留给Wil
and in it I will my Wil back to Wil.
Wil会想要吗?
Will Wil want it?
Wil很嫌弃
Wil won't.
那个戒指盒是什么?
What's that ring box?
那是一枚
Oh. That is
订婚戒指
an engagement ring
我本来打算给我的女朋友Amy的
that I was going to give my girlfriend Amy.
什么!
What?!
你给她买了一枚戒指?
You bought her a ring?
这是我家祖传的
No, no, no. This has been in my family
只有一段时间遗失了
for generations. Except for a short time
就在Comanches切掉我曾曾曾祖母的手指
when Comanches cut off my great-great-great-grandmother's
偷了戒指的时候
finger and stole it.
可怜的Sheldon 太惨了
Sheldon, that's awful. No.
德州骑警一路追到他们的村子里
The Texas Rangers tracked them down to their village
把他们杀得一个不剩...
and slaughtered every last one of them, so...
结局还是很好的
it was a happy ending.
至少对我九指的祖母来说
Well, for my nine-fingered Nana.
说回戒指的事 Amy知道吗?
Okay, back to the ring. Does Amy even know about this?
不知道 在我说出来之前她就和我分手了
No. She broke up with me before I could broach the subject.
好可怜 那真是在你心上插了一刀啊
Oh, man, I'm sorry... that must have been devastating for you.
没有 我很好
No, not at all. No, I'm fine.
Amy对自己的感情有所保留
You know, Amy had reservations about our relationship,
所以现在一切都很好
so all worked out for the best.
- 我明白 只是...  - 我说了我没事!
- I know. It just...  - I said I'm fine!
我们跑题了
We've gotten a little off-topic.
让我来使一切重回精彩吧
Allow me to make things entertaining again
继续”Spock录片"
in this little Spockumentary.
那是Leonard的梗
That was Leonard's joke.
小时候 每当我进退两难
As a child, when faced with a dilemma,
我妈妈总是鼓励我问一句"耶稣会怎么做?"
my mother encouraged me to ask, "What would Jesus do?"
答案总是"爱你的邻居"
The answer to that was always, "Love thy neighbor."
但我的邻居满口蛀牙...
But my neighbor had a dead tooth, so...
所以这不可能了
that wasn't going to happen.
但是...
But...
这也让我转而问"Spock会怎么做?"
that's why I changed it to, "What would Spock do?"
那样有用吗?
Did you find that helpful?
是的 例如 三年前
Yes. Oh, for example, three years ago
当我发现Penny偷吃我的Pop-Tarts的时候
when I discovered Penny was eating all my Pop-Tarts,
比起怀恨在心
instead of getting angry or vindictive,
我选择装一个地嵌保险箱
you know, I got a floor safe.
挡不住的香味啊
I knew I could smell 'em.
那你小的时候呢?
What about from when you were a kid?
当然了 在我八岁的时候
Oh, certainly. Uh, when I was eight years old,
Billy Sparks把我逼到操场的角落里
Billy Sparks cornered me in the playground.
我问自己"Spock会怎么做呢?"
I asked myself, "What would Spock do?"
我抓住了Billy的肩膀
Then I grabbed Billy on his shoulder
第一次实施了瓦肯擒拿术
and performed my first Vulcan nerve pinch.
起作用了?
Did it work?
没... 他打断了我的锁骨
Oh, no... he broke my collarbone.
我现在都能听到锁骨咔咔响
I can still hear it click.
你一定沮丧惨了
That must have been very upsetting for you.
才没有呢
Oh, not at all.
正如我说的 模仿Spock的精髓就在于
As I said, the entire point of emulating Spock
超越人类情感
was to rise above human emotion,
我会用尽一生去掌握
which I've spent a lifetime mastering.
呵呵
Oh...
你什么意思?
Excuse me?
不好意思 当我不存在
I'm sorry. I'm not here.
你嘘我了 什么意思?
No. You went... What does that mean?
额...
Um...
你确实嘘他了
You did go
好吧 Sheldon 虽然我不是专家
All right, fine. Well, Sheldon, I'm no expert,
但你是不是没抓住Spock的重点呢?
but aren't you completely missing the point of Spock?
虽然他表现得像是没有感情
I mean, he liked to act
但他还是有一半人类基因啊
like he had no emotions, but he was still half human.
和你一样
Just like you.
你表现得没有感情
I'm just saying, you pretend you don't,
但你也还是一个有血有肉的人
but you have feelings just like everybody else.
不是的 看着我
Not true. No, look at me.
我打算向一个女孩求婚
I had an engagement ring to give a girl,
但她拒绝了我
and instead, she rejected me.
我变得情绪化了吗? 没有
And am I emotional about that? No.
我坐在沙发上
No, I am sitting here on a couch,
谈论着我最喜欢的电视人物
talking about my favorite TV character
就像什么都没发生
like nothing happened.
因为我和Spock一样 永远只有逻辑和理性
'Cause I am just like him: all logical, all the time.
亲爱的 你都开始冲我喊了
Sweetie, you're yelling.
因为我用正常声音说话的时候
Because when I speak at a regular volume,
你们都不相信
no one seems to believe me
我早就不在乎Amy什么的了!
that I've put this Amy nonsense behind me!
这个纪录片绝对超赞的
This documentary is gonna be awesome.
- 你在这里感觉还好嘛?  - 没事 挺好的
- You gonna be okay down here?  - Yeah. Yeah,
我感觉自己像个考古学家
I feel like an archaeologist.
像是Indiana Jones与独栋别墅
Indiana Jones and the Single-Family Dwelling.
嘿 看啊!
Hey. Look!
我捡了个贝壳
Found a seashell.
其实是老鼠的骨头
Yeah, that's a rat skull.
淡定
Relax.
这的灰尘够多的了 你就别再折腾了
There's enough droppings down here without you making more.
抱歉 你知道... 这里是什么位置吗?
Sorry. Do you have a... sense of where we are?
大概吧 我觉得那边是小客厅
Yeah. I think that's the den.
好吧 那这里就是餐厅了
Oh. Okay, so we must be under the dining room.
没错
Uh-huh. Yep.
那个 我知道你可能不太想听我说这件事
You know, I know you don't want to hear this,
不过把小客厅改造成婴儿室
but it wouldn't take that much work to turn that den
也不会很费事
into a nursery.
我为什么会不想听你说这件事?
Why wouldn't I want to hear it?
因为Bernie说你不想要孩子
'Cause Bernie said you didn't want kids.
不是这样的
That's not true at all.
我... 我很希望
I... I wish
她能怀上一个宝宝 真的
she'd get pregnant, believe me.
一有机会我就扑倒她
I'm climbing on top of her every chance I get.
那个... 当然我也很温柔的
In a... loving and respectful manner.
唔
Oh.
重点是
The point is,
我真的很想要孩子
I really do want kids.
是嘛
Huh.
我不知道她为什么没跟你说实话
I don't know why she's lying to you.
不过 明明是她不想要孩子的
She's the one who doesn't want kids.
而且 每次我提起这件事的时候...
In fact, every time I bring up the subject...
地震啦!
Earthquake!
天啊 咱俩死定了!
Oh, my God, we're gonna die!
地震啦!
Earthquake!
余震啦...!
Aftershock...!
我真不敢相信 Sheldon居然想向Amy求婚来着
I can't believe Sheldon was gonna ask Amy to marry him.
是啊 我也完全没想到
I know. I also can't believe
他看了我们在沙发上做的事之后
he watched what we did on that couch
- 还继续坐在那里  - 是啊
- and still sits on it.  - Yeah.
嗨
Hello.
嘿 你怎么样了?
Hey, buddy. How you doing?
好点了
Better.
- Will和Adam都走了吗?  - 走了
- Did Wil and Adam leave?  - Yeah.
你说他们会不会把我情绪失控的样子
Do you think they're going to put my outburst
也放在纪录片里播出来?
in the documentary?
- 绝对会  - 肯定的
- Definitely.  - Oh, yeah.
再这样纠结下去一点意义也没有
Well, there's no point in dwelling on it.
就像瓦肯人说的那样
As the Vulcans say,
"你能让被你杀死的东西起死回生吗" (瓦肯语)
"Kup-fun-tor ha'kiv na'ish Du stau."
- 你知道这句话是什么意思吗?  - 不知道
- Do you know what that means?  - No.
真的吗?
Are you telling the truth?
假的 (瓦肯语)
Nirsh.
我这个样子太荒唐了 一直为Amy的事纠结
Well, this is ridiculous. Being upset about Amy
是不会有任何帮助的
all the time isn't accomplishing anything.
我要是想解决这个问题
If I want to resolve this situation,
就需要付诸行动
then I need to take action.
- 你要干嘛?  - 我要去找她
- What are you gonna do?  - I'm going to find her
问她愿不愿意嫁给我
and ask her to marry me.
如果她说愿意 这事就算过去了
And if she says yes, we can put this behind us
我们可以恢复我们的关系
and resume our relationship.
如果她不愿意...
And if she says no...
那她就可以"去死了(瓦肯语)"
well, then she can just ponfo miran.
他开玩笑的
He didn't meant that.
我觉得我大概有必要解释一下为什么撒谎
So I should probably explain why I kind of fibbed.
你最好解释一下
That would be nice.
我跟我老爸说 是你不想要孩子
I told my dad that you were the one
因为我不想让他失望
who didn't want kids because I didn't want to disappoint him.
那你觉得让我背这个锅就没问题了?
But you were okay throwing me under the bus?
看起来是没什么问题啊 我也没多想
Turns out yeah, I didn't think twice about it.
Bernie 你不用考虑我是怎么想的
Bernie, you don't need to worry about me.
可是我不希望你失去这个机会
But I don't want to see you miss out.
把你带大
Raising children
是我这辈子最有收获的一件事
was the most rewarding experience of my life.
得了吧 所有事都是妈妈做的
Oh, please. Mom did everything.
你就是每天下了班
All you did was come home from work,
回家坐在沙发上喝啤酒
sit on the couch and drink beer.
这和带孩子有什么关系?
How is that raising kids?
还是你们夫妻俩
This is really
好好聊聊这件事吧
a conversation for husband and wife.
我去收拾干净就先走了
I'm gonna go clean up, hit the road.
对了 要是你妈问起来 就说我在这待到十点多才走
If your mother asks, I was here till 10:00.
真有意思 你老爸并没帮上什么忙
It's interesting your father didn't help around the house
Howard也没有
and Howard doesn't help, either,
所以... 从某种角度上来看
so... in a way,
Howard不光像你老爸
Howard's not only like your father,
还像你不太想要的那个孩子
but he's also like the child that you're afraid to have.
你为什么还不走?
Why are you still here?
好吧 我这就撤
Fine, I'll leave.
不过我感觉有人得换尿布了
But it sounds like somebody needs a fresh diaper.
好吧...
All right...
我承认... 我没帮上什么大忙
I admit... that I don't help out a lot.
这一点我还要努力
And I need to work on that.
不过...
But...
如果我有个孩子的话
if we had a kid,
我一定会有所不同的
it would be different.
- 为什么?  - 因为...
- Why?  - Because...
我父亲离开的时候
when my dad left,
我曾经对自己保证过...
I promised myself that...
如果有一天 我也能成为一个父亲的话...
if I ever had a chance to be a father...
我一定会永远陪在孩子身边
I'd always be there.
好吧 我好好考虑一下这件事
Okay, I'll think about it.
你是说认真的会"好好考虑一下"
And this an actual "I'll think about it,"
而不是“能不能买个带副驾的摩托
not like the "can we get a motorcycle
我会考虑一下”的意思吗?
with a sidecar I'll think about it"?
我真的会"好好考虑一下"
It's an actual "I'll think about it."
我一定可以做一个好父亲的
I really believe I'd be a great dad.
我相信你
I know you would.
既然说到生孩子...
Speaking of...
要不要我现在洗洗干净
making babies, what do you say I wash up
然后也来探索一下你的狭小的空间?
and poke around your crawlspace?
Dana医生觉得他没有那么危险
Dr.Dana feels he isn't that dangerous.
凭什么你的判断是对的 而一个有经验的精神科医生是错的?
What makes you right and a trained psychiatrist wrong?
因为她有感情 而我没有
Because she feels. I don't.
我只知道逻辑
All I know is logic.
是啊 没错
Yeah, right.
你倒是可以说没感情就没感情
You can just shut your feelings off.
电视剧又一次欺骗了我们
There goes television, lying to us again.
我们都放心把孩子
We let you
托付给你们了
raise our children,
你们就这样回报我们的
and this is the thanks we get.
Leonard 你说我怎么会愚蠢到
Leonard, how could I have been so foolish
想要像一个电视剧里的
to try and follow in the footsteps
虚拟的外星人一样没有感情?
of a made-up alien race with no emotions?
其实...
Well...
你现在不再崇拜虚拟的角色了
now instead of idolizing fictional characters,
可以多关注一下你生活中的人
you can focus on the real people who are already in your life.
说的有道理
Those are very wise words.
谢了
Thank you.
要是这句话是电视剧里出现的
They'd just be so much more comforting
就更能安慰到我了
if they came out of a television.